# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, I am Wang Gang
# 今天我想跟大家分享一个翻锅的小技巧
Today, I will be sharing some techniques of wok tossing.
# 我的教学视频 做菜教学当中从来没有这个翻锅的小技巧
In my previous videos, I have never taught these techniques to you.
# 以前我以为在家里面吧
I thought home cooking
# 大家可能不怎么会用得上这个翻锅的一些技巧
Does not require wok tossing
# 其实我觉得应该是我错了
But I was wrong
# 其实大家最渴望最基本的应该就是第一步 从翻锅开始
In fact, the most basic thing everyone desires are wok tossing
# 今天我就来跟大家分享
I am sharing this with you guys today
# 包括从怎么样去用这个抓锅布到怎么样子去翻做第一节课
Including how to use wok towel to toss the wok
# 好 现在我们来开始来切这个布
Now, let’s cut this towel
# 我们一般厨房里面用的是这种毛巾
Normally, I use this type of kitchen towel
# 这个专门（用）做厨房里面的纯白色毛巾
This cloth was designed to be used in kitchen
# 用来擦东西 也可以用来做抓锅布
You can wipe things with it, or use it as a wok towel
# 然后今天就用这个来切一块下来
Now, let’s cut this towel in half
# 我们叠这个毛巾的方法有很多
There are many ways to fold the towel
# 我今天就跟大家分享一个最简单的
I am going to share the easiest one with you
# 首先把这个布叠得这么宽
First, fold this towel like this
# 根据你自己的手掌这样子试一下
Use your palm to measure the width
# 差不多的话再往外面叠 再叠一层
And fold it one more time.
# OK 然后这里给它切掉
OK cut it from here
# 好 然后我们直接对折过来
And then, we fold it like this
# 对折过来了之后待会儿我们上锅的时候把这个卡到耳朵里面就可以了
Now, let’s put the towel into the handle of the wok
# 这是最简单最普通的一个做法
And this is the easiest way to do it
# 然后我们还有一种拿抓锅布的办法是这样子的
There is another way to grab the towel as well
# 两只手（指）夹住这里
Use these two fingers to hold here
# 然后这边拿过来这样子
And grab here
# 这个是随拿随走
The towel goes with your hand
# 我们手离开锅的时候 是拿着毛巾一起离开的
When we’re letting our hand off the wok, we grab the towel with us
# 还有一种就是直接挂在上面 挂在锅上面直接这样子拿的
You can hang your towel on the handle like this as well
# 好了 我们现在来试一下第一种
Alright, let’s try the first way to do it
# 第一种就是经常在我视频当中可以看到的直接挂上去
Normally, I just hang my towel on the handle in my videos
# 这样子这个布直接挂上去 这样就可以
Hang it on here, just like that
# 这个做法的话适合于我们川菜厨师 大部分都是这样子
Most Sichuanese chefs do it like that
# 因为简单省事儿
Easy and convince
# 还有另外一种是粤菜厨师非常喜欢的
Another way is widely used by Cantonese chefs
# 就刚刚我说的两根手指夹住它
Hold it by two fingers
# 然后手张开翻过来这样子拿
Open the palm and flip it like this
# 他是抓着这个抓锅布翻翻翻
Toss the wok like this
# 翻好了之后 他如果是打调料的话这个布是跟着手一起过来的
Grab the towel with you when you going to get some spices
# 其实如果你说哪一样更实用的话我觉得这个是更加实用的 简单直接
If you ask me which one do I prefer, I think the first one is better
# 我们新手的话这样就OK了
It works for beginners
# 好了 下面来分享一下翻锅的一些规则小技巧
Ok let me show you some tips to toss the wok
# 首先我们翻锅的话不要着急 急着翻
Firstly, do not rush to toss
# 我们先来第一步 就是拉锅 直线拉锅
Let’s learn how to pull the wok
# 直线拉锅现在锅放在这个位置
Straightly pull the wok like this, place the wok over here
# 把它拉出来 拉出三分之一的位置
About one third
# 大概是这个位置 三分之一
Roughly one third
# 然后我们再把它放下去
And then place it down
# 放下去放到什么位置呢 只要说不撞到这里就OK
Make sure the side of the wok doesn’t touch the wok station when you push it back
# 这样子 我们先练习这一步
Let’s practice that
# 这一步一般练习三天
Usually, it takes three days to practice
# 这一步的目的就是锻炼你左手的力气
The purpose of this is the strengthen your left hand
# 然后是说推出去拉回来的这一步走直线
Pull and push the wok on a straight line
# 不能够歪 歪了的话就会这样子
Don’t go zig zag
# 你中间的菜就会翻不过来
Your ingredient wont flip over if you do that
# 然后到我后面来看一下
Go behind me and check this out
# 从我肩膀 左肩的这个位置
From my left shoulder
# 左肩锁骨这个位置 这里出去一条直线
From my left collarbone, push the wok on the straight line
# 好 现在我们第一步会了之后来第二步
Let’s move on to the next step
# 第二步的话它就要出去之后有一个弧度上来
In the second step, it requires a curve to do
# 同样也是锅拉出来不要超出三分之一 这个位置左右
Same as the first step, pull up wok out on one third of the wok
# 然后下去了之后一点点弧度上来 下去上来
And then push it back, and pull it up again with an curve
# 好 我们再从我的后面来 锁骨的这个位置来看一下
Go behind me again to check it from my collarbone
# 好 这些我们练会了之后然后才开始拿勺子
After that, lets use the chef spoon
# 右手拿勺 拿勺子的话 勺子主要的目的是什么
Hold it on your right hand
# 这样子出去的时候 菜到这个位置它不会翻过来的
The purpose of it is to make sure your ingredients can flip over
# 需要用勺子把它推起来 推得时候推推
Use you spoon to push it up
# 但是回来的时候这边就不要刮到这边
And don’t touch this side on the way back
# 好 今天就跟你们先分享到这里
Alright, that’s it today
# 就是说这三个动作 拉
Three moves, pull
# 好 到第二个动作下去的时候有一定的弧度
Push with a curve
# 第三个动作才开始拿勺子 推 炒
And push with your spoon and start stir fry
# 好了 本期视频就先跟你们聊到这里
Ok, that’s today
# 下一期视频我会教大家放东西进去把它翻起来
In the next video, I’ll show you how to stir-fry with ingredients inside the wok
# 好了 拜拜
Bye bye